Guide to the Gabon Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Gabon collection
1950-2012
MS 1517
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to historical, political, and social conditions in Gabon.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original collection is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to historical, political, and social conditions in Gabon.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Women -- Gabon; Gabon -- Politics and government; Gabon -- Social conditions; Rassemblement national-bûcherons (Gabon); Société nationale des bois du Gabon; Union socialiste gabonaise
- Inventory, 1969-1990
  - Political organizations: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1969-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic journals; printed material, [1979?], undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Government documents; journals; reports, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Feminism/women's rights: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, 1950, 1990-1996; Accession 1995-M-175
  - General information
    - "Le Gabon: Carte de Visite" [tourist pamphlet], Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Souvenirs Sur Le Gabon, 1950
  - Coordination de L'Opposition Democrate – Contre – Sommet de Libreville du 4 au 8 Octobre 1992 – Various Papers (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contributions à la Démocratie Gabonaise, vol. 1, Union Socialiste Gabonaise (USG), 1992 May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ntoutoume Ndzeng, Samuel. "La Constitution Française de 1958 Serait à L'Origine de la Durée des Chefs d'Etat Africains Au Pouvoirs...?," Recherches Politiques Operationnelles Pour Culture Populaire, vol. 1, no. 5, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Parti Démocratique Gabonais, statutes of, [199-] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rassemblement National-Bûcher (Gabon)
    - Projet de Société du RNB, 1993 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Règlement Intérieur RNB, 1993 June 6
  - Société Nationale des Bois du Gabon (SNBG), general information, [199-] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1990-1994, undated; Accession 2010-M-105
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged as received.
  - Misamu, 1994 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Passion de L' Unité, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Publication of Union Socialiste Gabonaise (U.S.G.)
  - La Nouvelle Démocratie, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Voix du Peuple, 1994 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Relance, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Les Compagnons de la Libération Economique du Gabon, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Griffe: Journal Satirique Indépendant, 1991 April 12, 1994 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le Bûcheron, 1991 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - La Clé: Le Journal du Peuple, 1991 April 10-16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aperçu sur le Gabon, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L'Assemblée Nationale, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1990, 2012; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1990, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)